[
    {
        "question": "The instrument that measures and records the relative humidity of air is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Hydrometer"
            },
            {
                "option": "Hygrometer"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Lactometer"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Barometer"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Hygrometer",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The shape of our milky way galaxy is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Circular"
            },
            {
                "option": "Elliptical"
            },
            {
                "option": "Spiral"
            },
            {
                "option": "Nose of the above"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Spiral",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The different colors of different stars are due to the variation of_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Temperature"
            },
            {
                "option": "Pressure"
            },
            {
                "option": "Density"
            },
            {
                "option": "Radiation from tehm"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Temperature",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fundamental scientific principle in the operation of battery is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Acid-base interaction"
            },
            {
                "option": "Dialysis"
            },
            {
                "option": "Dissociation of electrolytes"
            },
            {
                "option": "Oxidation-reduction"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Dissociation of electrolytes",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Instrument used to measure the force and velocity of the wind is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Ammeter"
            },
            {
                "option": "Anemometer"
            },
            {
                "option": "Altimeter"
            },
            {
                "option": "Audiometer"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Anemometer",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which combination of color the most convenient during day and night time ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Orange and blue"
            },
            {
                "option": "White and black"
            },
            {
                "option": "Yellow and blue"
            },
            {
                "option": "Red and green"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Red and green",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Woolen clothes keep the body warm because_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Wool increses the temperature of the body"
            },
            {
                "option": "Wool is a bad conductor"
            },
            {
                "option": "Wool absorbs radiant heat from outer objects"
            },
            {
                "option": "Wool rejects heat from the outer objects"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Wool is a bad conductor",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the length of a simple pendulum is halved then its period of oscillation is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "doubled"
            },
            {
                "option": "halved"
            },
            {
                "option": "increased by a factor"
            },
            {
                "option": "decreased by a factor"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"decreased by a factor",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Equilibrium is a condition that can_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "never change"
            },
            {
                "option": "change only if some outside factor changes"
            },
            {
                "option": "change only if some internal factor changes"
            },
            {
                "option": "change only if government policies change"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"never change",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "While catching a ball, a player pulls down his hands to lower the ",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "force"
            },
            {
                "option": "moment"
            },
            {
                "option": "impulse"
            },
            {
                "option": "catching time"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"impulse",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Geostationary satellite revolves at",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "any height"
            },
            {
                "option": "fixed height"
            },
            {
                "option": "height which depends upon its mass"
            },
            {
                "option": "height above pole"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"fixed height",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a barometer reading suddenly recedes, it indicates that climate_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "will be very warm"
            },
            {
                "option": "will be extremely stormy"
            },
            {
                "option": "will remain cold"
            },
            {
                "option": "incessant rain for at least 48 hours"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"will be extremely stormy",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "A particle dropped from the top of a tower uniformly falls on ground at a distance which is equal to the height of tower. Which of the following paths will be traversed by the particly ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Circle"
            },
            {
                "option": "Parabolic"
            },
            {
                "option": "Great circle"
            },
            {
                "option": "Hyper-parabolic"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Parabolic",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asteroids revolve round the Sun between which of the following two planets ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Earth and Mars"
            },
            {
                "option": "Mars and Jupiter"
            },
            {
                "option": "Jupiter Saturn"
            },
            {
                "option": " Saturn and Uranus"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Mars and Jupiter",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Smog is a general pollutant where_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "temperature is high"
            },
            {
                "option": "temperture is low"
            },
            {
                "option": "air contains excess ammonia"
            },
            {
                "option": "air contains excess SO2"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"air contains excess SO2",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of light with the rise in the temperature of teh medium",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Increases"
            },
            {
                "option": "Decreases"
            },
            {
                "option": "Remains unaltered"
            },
            {
                "option": "Drops suddenly"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Remains unaltered",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cloths keep us warm in winter because they_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "suppy heat"
            },
            {
                "option": "don't radiate heat"
            },
            {
                "option": "prevent air from contacting the body"
            },
            {
                "option": "prevent the heat of the body from excaping"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"prevent the heat of the body from excaping",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a refrigerator what produces the cooling",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "the ice deposits on the freezer"
            },
            {
                "option": "The sudden expansion of a comporessed gas"
            },
            {
                "option": "The evaporation of a volatile liquid"
            },
            {
                "option": "None of these above"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"The evaporation of a volatile liquid",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are we able to hear short wave broadcasts etter than long wave broadcasts ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Short waves are more energetic than long waves."
            },
            {
                "option": "Short waves are unaffected by atmospheric disturbances."
            },
            {
                "option": "Short wave broadcasts are made by nearby radio stations."
            },
            {
                "option": "By convention, short waves are meant for long distances, whereas long waves are reserved for short distances"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Short waves are unaffected by atmospheric disturbances.",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electron microscope was invented by_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Knoll and Ruska"
            },
            {
                "option": "Robert Koch"
            },
            {
                "option": "Leeuwenhock"
            },
            {
                "option": "CP. Swan son"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Knoll and Ruska",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "A passenger standing in a bus is thrown outward when the bu takes a sudden turn. This happens due to_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Outward pull on him"
            },
            {
                "option": "Inertia of motion"
            },
            {
                "option": "Change in momentum"
            },
            {
                "option": "change in acceleration"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Inertia of motion",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not true for Geostationary Satellite ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Its time period is 24 hours"
            },
            {
                "option": "Its angular speed is equal to that of earth about its own axis"
            },
            {
                "option": "It is fixed in space"
            },
            {
                "option": "It revolves from west to east ove the equator"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"It is fixed in space",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "When pressure is increased the melting point of ice_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "increases"
            },
            {
                "option": "does not change"
            },
            {
                "option": "decreases"
            },
            {
                "option": "depends on the impurities in the ice"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"decreases",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal waves can't travel through_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Vacuum"
            },
            {
                "option": "Solid"
            },
            {
                "option": "Liquid"
            },
            {
                "option": "Gas"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Vacuum",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrostatic precipitator is used to control the pollution of",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "air"
            },
            {
                "option": "water"
            },
            {
                "option": "noise"
            },
            {
                "option": "thermal"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"air",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "When two ice cubes are pressed over each other they unite to form one cube, because of",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "vander Waal's forces"
            },
            {
                "option": "dipole moment"
            },
            {
                "option": "hydrogen bond formation"
            },
            {
                "option": "covalent attraction"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"hydrogen bond formation",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following parts of the sunlight makes the solar cooker hot?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Ultraviolet"
            },
            {
                "option": "Redlight"
            },
            {
                "option": "Infrared"
            },
            {
                "option": "Cosmic"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Infrared",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the velocity-time graph of a particle is represented by y=mt+v, then the particle is moving with____",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "constant speed"
            },
            {
                "option": "constant velocity"
            },
            {
                "option": "constant acceleration"
            },
            {
                "option": "varying acceleratin"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"constant acceleration",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following occured first?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Albert Einstein propounded the General Theory of Relativity"
            },
            {
                "option": "Max planck unveiled the Quantum Theory"
            },
            {
                "option": "Guglielmo Marconi sent out the first wireless signals"
            },
            {
                "option": "Wright brothers sucessfully flew an aircraft"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Guglielmo Marconi sent out the first wireless signal",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The animal uses sounds as its 'eyes' is ____",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Dog"
            },
            {
                "option": "Cat"
            },
            {
                "option": "Snake"
            },
            {
                "option": "Bat"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Bat",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sky appears blue because of ______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Atmospheric water vapour"
            },
            {
                "option": "Scattering of light"
            },
            {
                "option": "Reflection on sea water"
            },
            {
                "option": "Emission of blue wavelength by the sun"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Scattering of light",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dynamo is a device for coverting___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Heat energy into electrical energy"
            },
            {
                "option": "Mechanical energy into electrical energy"
            },
            {
                "option": "Magnetic energy into electrical energy"
            },
            {
                "option": "Chemical energy into electrical energy"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Mechanical energy into electrical energy",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The working of quartz crystal in the watch is based on ___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Johnson effect"
            },
            {
                "option": "Photoelectric effect"
            },
            {
                "option": "Edison effect"
            },
            {
                "option": "Piezo electric effect"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Piezo electric effect",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oil rises up the wick in a lamp because, ",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "oil is very light"
            },
            {
                "option": "of the diffusion of oil through the wick"
            },
            {
                "option": "of the surface tension phenomenon"
            },
            {
                "option": "Of the capillary action phenomenon"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Of the capillary action phenomenon",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the atmosphere ultraviolet rays are absorbed by __",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Oxygen"
            },
            {
                "option": "Nitrogen"
            },
            {
                "option": "Ozone"
            },
            {
                "option": "Helium"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Ozone",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following cryogenic engines are used?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Frost-free refrigerators"
            },
            {
                "option": "Sub-marine propulsion"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rockets"
            },
            {
                "option": "Researchers in super conductivity"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Rockets",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of the space shuttle that landed man on the moon?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Eagle"
            },
            {
                "option": "Columbia"
            },
            {
                "option": "Challenger"
            },
            {
                "option": "Apollo"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Apollo",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "The energy emitted by the sun is due to ___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Chemical reaction"
            },
            {
                "option": "Nuclear fission"
            },
            {
                "option": "Nuclear fusion"
            },
            {
                "option": "ALl of the above"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Nuclear fusion",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tungsten is used for the manufacture of the filament of an electric bulb , because___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Its a good conductor"
            },
            {
                "option": "Its economical"
            },
            {
                "option": "Its malleable"
            },
            {
                "option": "It has a very high melting point"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"It has a very high melting point",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who measured the velocity of light first?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Galileo"
            },
            {
                "option": "Newton"
            },
            {
                "option": "Romer"
            },
            {
                "option": "Einstein"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Romer",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following alloy is used in making magnet?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Duralumin"
            },
            {
                "option": "Stainless steel"
            },
            {
                "option": "Elniko"
            },
            {
                "option": "Magnalium"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Elniko",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are mesons found?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Cosmic rays"
            },
            {
                "option": "X-rays"
            },
            {
                "option": "Gamma rays"
            },
            {
                "option": "Laser beam"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Cosmic rays",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lamberts law is related to _______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Reflection"
            },
            {
                "option": "Refraction"
            },
            {
                "option": "Interference"
            },
            {
                "option": "Illumination"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Illumination",
        "tag" : "physics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following laws validates the statement that matter can neither be created nor destroyed?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Law of conservation of energy"
            },
            {
                "option": "Le chatelier's principle"
            },
            {
                "option": "Law of conservation of Mass"
            },
            {
                "option": "Law of osmosis"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Law of conservation of Mass",
        "tag" : "physics"
    }
]
